<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tax Help for Part-Time Uber Drivers on YMiles Rideshare</title>
    <link>https://ymiles.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tax Help for Part-Time Uber Drivers on YMiles Rideshare</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://ymiles.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ymiles.com/cpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ymiles.com/cpa/</guid>
      <description>Help Us Build YMiles, a Family-First LLC Strategy Seeking an experienced CPA to support our tax strategy, family payroll, and long-term wealth goals&#xA;About Our LLC We’ve recently converted a high-paying W-2 DevOps job into an LLC that earns $230,000 annually. This LLC has two operating divisions:&#xA;Division 1: YMiles – Focused on rideshare tax education and services, digital content, and YouTube monetization (no revenue yet) Division 2: DevOps Consulting – Provides infrastructure and automation services Our vision is to run both divisions under one LLC structure that enables long-term tax planning, retireent contributions, and family employment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ymiles.com/dead-head-miles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ymiles.com/dead-head-miles/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Dead Head Miles Not all miles are created equal — at least not according to the IRS. If you&amp;rsquo;re an Uber driver, it&amp;rsquo;s important to know which miles are deductible and which aren’t. One gray area for many drivers is dead head miles — the miles you drive between trips, or while repositioning.&#xA;Here’s what the IRS says:&#xA;You cannot deduct the miles from your home to your first rider pickup unless you&amp;rsquo;re using the app and receive a ping before leaving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do I Need to File a Schedule C?</title>
      <link>https://ymiles.com/schedule-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ymiles.com/schedule-c/</guid>
      <description>What Is Schedule C and Why Uber Drivers Need It If you drive for Uber — even part time — you’re considered self-employed by the IRS. That means you don’t receive a W-2, and Uber doesn’t withhold taxes from your payouts. Instead, you’re responsible for reporting your income and expenses using a form called Schedule C.&#xA;Schedule C is where you calculate your net profit as a business. It’s where you report the income from your 1099-K and 1099-NEC, then subtract all of your deductions like mileage, Uber fees, phone use, and car cleaning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is It Worth Tracking Dead Head Miles for Previous Years?</title>
      <link>https://ymiles.com/amend-taxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ymiles.com/amend-taxes/</guid>
      <description>Go Back and Save: Dead Head Miles from Past Years Still Count! If you’ve been driving for Uber part time and haven’t been tracking dead head miles, you could be leaving hundreds of dollars in unclaimed deductions on the table — even from previous tax years.&#xA;The IRS allows you to amend your tax return for up to three years, which means you can still go back and claim mileage you missed — including deadhead miles Uber didn’t track for you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quareterly Taxes</title>
      <link>https://ymiles.com/quarterly-taxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ymiles.com/quarterly-taxes/</guid>
      <description>Do I Need to Pay Quarterly Taxes as an Uber Driver? If you drive for Uber part-time, you may have heard that self-employed people are required to make quarterly estimated tax payments. While that’s true for some drivers, it likely doesn’t apply to you — and here’s why.&#xA;The IRS only requires quarterly tax payments if you expect to owe more than $1,000 in taxes at the end of the year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thank You</title>
      <link>https://ymiles.com/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ymiles.com/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>✅ You&amp;rsquo;re All Set! Check your inbox — your YMiles Checklist is on its way! 📬&#xA;If you don’t see it in a few minutes, check your Spam or Promotions tab.&#xA;⬅️Back to Home</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thanks for Reaching Out</title>
      <link>https://ymiles.com/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ymiles.com/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>Thanks! Your message was sent successfully. I’ll be in touch soon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uber Driver Tax Deductions</title>
      <link>https://ymiles.com/deductions-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ymiles.com/deductions-checklist/</guid>
      <description>Uber Driver Deductions Checklist As a part-time Uber driver, one of the easiest ways to reduce your tax bill is by claiming the right deductions. This checklist breaks them into three categories to make filing simple.&#xA;1. Mileage Log Book (Built with My Tool) The IRS requires a log book to claim mileage deductions. If you&amp;rsquo;re ever audited, a general summary from Uber is not enough — it must show dates, miles, and purpose of each trip.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uber Driver Tax Pricing</title>
      <link>https://ymiles.com/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ymiles.com/training/</guid>
      <description>Get the Right Training — Free or Premium Learn how to file your Uber taxes the right way with short videos and matching articles. Whether you want to understand 1099s, mileage tracking, or quarterly taxes, this page keeps everything organized in one place.&#xA;Free Training (Videos + Blog Posts) 1. How to Use the 1099-K 🎥 Watch on YouTube 📄 Read the Matching Blog&#xA;2. What to Do with the 1099-NEC 🎥 Watch on YouTube 📄 Read the Matching Blog</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Your 1099-K</title>
      <link>https://ymiles.com/1099-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ymiles.com/1099-k/</guid>
      <description>What Is the 1099-K and Why Did I Get It? If you’re a part-time Uber driver, the tax paperwork can be overwhelming. One form you’ll almost always hear about is the 1099-K, which Uber may send to report your earnings. This guide will walk you through what the 1099-K is, how to read it, and — most importantly — how to use it with other Uber documents to accurately calculate what you owe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using the 1099-NEC</title>
      <link>https://ymiles.com/1099-nec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ymiles.com/1099-nec/</guid>
      <description>How to Use the 1099-NEC From Uber When you&amp;rsquo;re a part-time Uber driver, you may receive more than one tax form. While most people know about the 1099-K, Uber drivers may also receive a 1099-NEC. This form reports income that didn&amp;rsquo;t come directly from your passengers, and it often catches drivers off guard.&#xA;This guide explains what the 1099-NEC is, why you might receive one, and how to use it alongside your 1099-K and Uber Tax Summary to file your taxes correctly — without paying more than you need to.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
